<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Programming on Clint Rori</title><link>https://rorimwema.github.io/categories/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on Clint Rori</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rorimwema.github.io/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>So You Want to Be a Programmer</title><link>https://rorimwema.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rorimwema.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So you want to be a programmer. You think it is about computers, about code, about some neat abstractions stacked in your head. But really, it is about patience and curiosity and the relentless itch of wanting to see what happens when you poke at the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming is not glamorous. It is not about showing off frameworks or boasting about your GitHub streak. It is about sitting there, staring at a problem, feeling your brain ache a little, and then — suddenly — a door opens, a tiny mechanism clicks, and the machine obeys. That moment is bliss, more than any job title or paycheck.&lt;/p&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So you want to be a programmer. You think it is about computers, about code, about some neat abstractions stacked in your head. But really, it is about patience and curiosity and the relentless itch of wanting to see what happens when you poke at the world.</p>
<p>Programming is not glamorous. It is not about showing off frameworks or boasting about your GitHub streak. It is about sitting there, staring at a problem, feeling your brain ache a little, and then — suddenly — a door opens, a tiny mechanism clicks, and the machine obeys. That moment is bliss, more than any job title or paycheck.</p>
<p>Charles Bukowski said writing is a gut feeling, a way to bleed yourself onto the page. Programming is the same, only your bleeding is logic, your words are functions, your paragraphs are data structures. Sussman would tell you it is about understanding the system, the abstraction, not just hacking on the surface. Paul Graham would tell you to build something people want, to start with what fascinates you, and then sweat the details until your code becomes invisible, elegant, and powerful.</p>
<p>If you want to be a programmer, be prepared to fail. Be prepared to love the failures, because every bug is a teacher, every crash is a conversation. Be authentic. Write code like you breathe — messy, desperate, alive.</p>
<p>Programming is not a career. It is a calling. And if you want it, you will not be stopped by languages, frameworks, or abstractions. You will be stopped only by yourself.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>