<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Poems &amp; Philosophy on Clint Rori</title><link>https://rorimwema.github.io/categories/poems--philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Poems &amp; Philosophy on Clint Rori</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2026 21:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rorimwema.github.io/categories/poems--philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Disappearance of Wonder</title><link>https://rorimwema.github.io/posts/dont-grow-up/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2026 21:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://rorimwema.github.io/posts/dont-grow-up/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Grow Up It&amp;rsquo;s a Scam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://tinyurl.com/nxmdpesb"
 alt="Don&amp;#39;t grow up" width="400"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children are interesting creatures. Alive with dreams, energy, a happiness that costs nothing. They inhabit wonder the way fish inhabit water naturally, completely, without knowing they are wet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then they are told to &amp;ldquo;grow up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society arrives with its expectations, its imaginary rulebook for how life must be lived. But here is what the rulebook never admits: it is written specifically to kill the thing that makes you human.&lt;/p&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Grow Up It&rsquo;s a Scam</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://tinyurl.com/nxmdpesb"
    alt="Don&#39;t grow up" width="400">
</figure>

<p>Children are interesting creatures. Alive with dreams, energy, a happiness that costs nothing. They inhabit wonder the way fish inhabit water naturally, completely, without knowing they are wet.</p>
<p>Then they are told to &ldquo;grow up.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Society arrives with its expectations, its imaginary rulebook for how life must be lived. But here is what the rulebook never admits: it is written specifically to kill the thing that makes you human.</p>
<p><strong>The Disappearance of Wonder</strong> happens slowly. It is not one dramatic death. It is a thousand small withdrawals. The tree stops being a castle and becomes lumber. The cloud stops being a dragon and becomes precipitation. The stranger stops being a potential friend and becomes a threat, a competitor, a demographic. You learn to measure everything time, love, success, beauty until nothing remains that cannot be weighed. The energy vanishes not because you aged, but because you stopped allowing yourself to be astonished.</p>
<p>You learn to wear masks. You pretend to be someone &ldquo;grown up,&rdquo; which mostly means someone bored, someone tired, someone who already knows how the story ends. Happiness becomes a metric, a checklist of requirements you must meet before you are allowed to feel it. Dreams shrink because someone drew a line between possible and impossible and you believed them. You stopped asking <em>why</em> and started asking <em>how much</em>.</p>
<p>Happy at heart, brain, and soul. If you, like me, have felt this fraud the sense that you are performing a role rather than living a life step back. Question everything you are right now. Ask who wrote the rules you follow. Ask when you last stood still simply because the light was hitting the wall in a way that made your chest ache.</p>
<p>Others will argue that people simply change. That this narrowing is natural, necessary, mature. But I think the child in you does not change. That child remains your light, your compass. The imagination was alive then not because you were naive, but because you were honest. The intentions were pure not because you were ignorant, but because you were true.</p>
<p>We follow our hearts by essence but if the heart is not pure, it misleads, and peace remains impossible.</p>
<p>So become the baby again. Let the wonder return. Look at the world as if you have never seen it, because in truth, you never have you have only been looking at your ideas about it. Only when the wonder returns does true imagination awaken. Only then do you live the life you love.</p>
<p>It is never too late.</p>
<p>As long as your heart beats.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Code of Silence</title><link>https://rorimwema.github.io/posts/the-code-of-silence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://rorimwema.github.io/posts/the-code-of-silence/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the quiet hum of the server room,
Where logic weaves its digital loom,
We trade in absolute, binary truth,
Seeking elegance in eternal youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But life is fuzzy, a float precision,
Full of race conditions and blurred vision.
We debug the world line by line,
Hoping the output will be divine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is the universe just a recursive call?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Or are we trapped in an endless &lt;code&gt;while(true)&lt;/code&gt; loop after all?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the quiet hum of the server room,
Where logic weaves its digital loom,
We trade in absolute, binary truth,
Seeking elegance in eternal youth.</p>
<p>But life is fuzzy, a float precision,
Full of race conditions and blurred vision.
We debug the world line by line,
Hoping the output will be divine.</p>
<p><em>Is the universe just a recursive call?</em>
<em>Or are we trapped in an endless <code>while(true)</code> loop after all?</em></p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>